Guide to the Lloyd Richards Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials, 1962-2004; Series VII; 10.44; (12 boxes)
  - Video Recordings
    - Interviews with Lloyd Richards
      - "WORLDNET 1336t/AFNET 121 Guest: Lloyd Richards", 1989 August 3; JWJMSS176_0116; 1; 00:59:10 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002093672864)
      - "CT Originals #7, 25, 26, 27, 29", 1987 January 9; JWJMSS176_0117; 1; 00:06:11 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002093672872)
        A typewritten note, dated 1987-02-27, is included with the tape. It reads: Dear Mr. Richards: Enclosed is a videocassette of the Connecticut Originals profiles you narrated. On behalf of SNET I'd like to thank you again for your participation in the program. I hope you enjoy viewing the tape. Sincerely, Marilyn Elperin/Account Executive
      - "Lloyd Richards Project", undated; JWJMSS176_0118; 1; 00:12:52; There is noise in the audio. (Box 153, Item barcode 39002093672880)
      - "Playwrights Conference Evening", 1999 May; JWJMSS176_0119; 1; 02:10:43; There is noise in the audio. (Box 153, Item barcode 39002093672898)
        This tape includes a note by "Mary". It reads: Lloyd, This is the tape of the LA party - Roger Christianson's students did it and he (Roger) did the editing. Hope you enjoy it. Mary
      - "Stephen Holt interviewing Athol Fugard and Yvonne Bryceland and Lloyd Richards", 1988 June; JWJMSS176_0068; 1; 00:45:07 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301083)
      - "Kennedy Center American Theater Festival: Lloyd Richards", undated; JWJMSS176_0070; 1; 01:59:32 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301109)
      - "Emerging Playwrights, Negro Ensemble, #10", 1979 November 29; JWJMSS176_0061; 1; 00:29:54 (Box 151, Item barcode 39002102301018)
      - "Emerging Playwrights #11", undated; JWJMSS176_0062; 1; 00:33:34 (Box 151, Item barcode 39002102301026)
      - "Emerging Playwrights (Jacker/Lloyd Richards) #12", undated; JWJMSS176_0063; 1; 00:31:43 (Box 151, Item barcode 39002102301034)
    - Other Recordings
      - "Video shown by Russians at 1983 NPC, Running time: 55 minutes", JWJMSS176_0065; 1; 01:00:04 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301059)
      - "Russian Dub" [Maybe dup of Video shown by Russians at 1983 NPC, Running time: 55 minutes], undated; JWJMSS176_0066; 1; 01:00:44 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301067)
      - "African Americans in Connecticut: The Civil War to Civil Rights," The Connecticut Experiencem, Connecticut Public Television and Radio, 2002; JWJMSS176_0067; 1; 00:59:31 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301075)
        A handwritten letter on CPTV letterhead, dated 2000-08-08, from filmmaker Karyl Evans to Lloyd Richards reads: Dear Mr. Richards, I hope this letter finds you well. As promised enclosed is a copy of the final show I produced and directed on the history of African Americans in CT. Thank you so very much for your participation. Kindest Regards, Karyl Evans. I'd love to know what you think of it.
      - "The Africans", undated; JWJMSS176_0069; 1; 05:43:40 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301091)
      - "American Theatre Wing: Guide to Careers in the Theatre, Susan Stroman, The Choreographer", 2001 October 2; JWJMSS176_0071; 1; 00:55:10 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301117)
        A memorandum, dated 2002-01-17, from Roy A. Somlyo of American Theatre Wing, Inc. to board members makes reference to the theatre's career guide series. This tape was sent to board members for viewing. Also included is a list of participants and the subjects covered in the series. Lloyd Richards is listed as an interviewee in the category of Director.
      - "American Theatre Wing Seminars Performance #298", 2001 Fall; JWJMSS176_0072; 1; 01:28:31 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301125)
      - "American Theatre Wing Seminars #300 The Playwright"/ Director Seminar, Spril 2002, 2002 April 23; JWJMSS176_0073; 1; 01:26:56 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301133)
        Panelists: Jon Robin Baitz, John Guare, Peter Parnell, Gene Saks, Daniel Sullivan, Mary Zimmerman. Moderator: Jeffrey Eric Jenkins.
      - "Brideshead Revisited, Volume II, Episodes VII-XI", undated; JWJMSS176_0074; 1; 04:49:59 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301141)
      - "Brideshead Revisited, Episodes I-VI", undated; JWJMSS176_0075; 1; 05:58:50 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301158)
      - "The Chickens", undated; JWJMSS176_0076; 1; 02:07:08 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301166)
        There is video about poultry and the chicken from 00:00:03-00:05:58. The rest of the tape consists of an X-Files episode and then, a "Tales From the Crypt" episode with Patricia Arquette. At 01:20:09, interviews and footage of Hugh Hefner abruptly begins and runs through the rest of the tape.
      - "1990 Connecticut Public Television Panel on the Arts", JWJMSS176_0077; 1; 00:32:09 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301174)
      - "Connecticut Arts Award 1982 Hayes intros White Richards Awards" CPTV, 1982 November 11; JWJMSS176_0078; 1; 00:14:00 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301182)
        There is a handwritten note from John Ostrout dated November 24th that reads: Dear Lloyd, I'm glad to enclose a copy of your CT. Arts Awards presentation - your acceptance was a highlight of the event. Hope all is well at the Rep and I hope to get to a performance in the near future. Best Wishes
      - "State of the Art, Connecticut Public Television", undated; JWJMSS176_0079; 1; 00:29:39; The video is overexposed. (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301190)
      - "MK CNN Interview", 1992 June 3; JWJMSS176_0080; 1; 00:55:08 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301208)
      - "MetroView: Center for Jewish History October 2000", 2000 October; JWJMSS176_0081; 1; 00:30:40 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301216)
      - "Maretha Auditions: 1) Stefana Sneed 2) Maria Martinez 3) Caristina Mitchell 4) Talia Carter", undated; JWJMSS176_0082; 1; 00:22:11 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301224)
        Part of an unidentified movie runs about 7 1/2 minutes at the beginning of the tape. The Maretha auditions begin at 00:07:32
      - "The Lions of Etosha / Gandhi", undated; JWJMSS176_0083; 1; 03:54:56 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301232)
      - "Lifetime Intimate Portrait: Jane Kaczmarek", undated; JWJMSS176_0084; 1; 00:44:18 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301240)
        Lloyd Richards is featured in the program. He was the former dean of the Yale School of Drama where Jane Kaczmarek attended.
      - "Journey to the Last Frontier by Ethan Gussow", undated; JWJMSS176_0085; 1; 00:22:35 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301257)
      - "Informed Sources #530 Master #BC998AML 'New York Theater'", 1996 May 30; JWJMSS176_0086; 1; 00:32:19 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301265)
      - "In the Moment Productions: Inside the Actors Studio, Laurence Fishburne", 1998 December 23; JWJMSS176_0087; 1; 00:58:19 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301281)
        A handwritten note from Valerie [?] from The Actors Studio MFA School of Dramatic Arts at New School University is included with the tape. It is dated 1999-02-26 and reads: Dear Mr. Richards, I have enclosed a copy of the Laurence Fishburne episode of "Inside the Actors Studio", which as you know was taped on September 22, 1998. Please do call our office directly at (212) 229-5612 if you would like to ask Jim Lipton or me any questions about the show or about our MFA program. Have a lovely weekend. Valerie [?]
      - "Democracy Now! Arundhati Roy in the DN studio", 2003 May 12; JWJMSS176_0088; 1; 00:59:44 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301299)
      - "Enchanted April / Belasco Theatre Press Footage Montage", undated; JWJMSS176_0089; 1; 00:01:53 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301307)
      - "CSUN Summer Arts 1986 – 1990 California State University", 1990 November 6; JWJMSS176_0090; 1; 00:09:11 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301315)
      - "Bob Hope Special, 85 years 50 NBC Lloyd Richards receives grant for Yale, 000 to to 1107", 1988 May 16; JWJMSS176_0091; 1; 03:00:20 (Box 152, Item barcode 39002102301323)
      - "Renaissance Revival: The First Black Theatre in America Conference 1992 NYU", JWJMSS176_0092; 1; 01:33:03 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301331)
        Parts: I, II, and III; 90 minutues
      - "Tommy Hollis/A Memorial Celebration/Friday November 9, 2001", 2001 November 9; JWJMSS176_0093; 1; 02:12:14 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301349)
        A note regarding actor Tommy Hollis dated January 23, 2002 is included with the tape. It is included, along with two bookmarks, in a folder in Box 153.
        The note reads: Dear Lloyd and Barbara -- Enclosed is a videotape of Tommy's Memorial, along with bookmarkers - one of them is especially made for Lloyd, with a pair of PEARS, walking side-by-side, as equals. It made Tommy feel so happy that you enjoyed the pears he sent. When I was packing up things in Tommy's apartment, I came across something that I am sure he intended to send to you. I know this was written recently, because I'm the one who gave him the computer and the printer, which had all the different typeface fonts - I had just taught him how to play around with different letterings. There is no doubt among all who knew him that Tommy reserved a special place in his heart for you. Tommy tried all of his father's life to prove that he was a good son, a worthy son. But Bob Hollis never understood his eldest son's sesitivities or artistry. Instead, Tommy was always punished for not going hunting with him. And every time Tommy was sent to his room, his little brother was the appointed "snitch," instructed to report all the times that Tommy would start writing: "Daddy, Tommy's writing again!" It's not that Bob Hollis didn't love his son. But as long as Tommy continued with artistic endeavors, he would never measure up as the man that his father demanded him to be, to walk alongside him, to carry on his name. Then, when his father died suddenly, those hopes of ever winning his respect died with him. "Thank you, Lloyd," he has said in our converstations many a time. To be able to be appreciated, loved, cared for nurtured, and finally, honored - all the things a child yearns for - you have given him. And now, perhaps a pre-destined plan from several lifetimes past, a soul pact with the strongest friend of one's lifetime: Tommy's best friend, Reggie Montgomery, has passed. As with Tommy, a friend went to his apartment when Reggie failed to return calls in a few days. The cops had to climb the fire escape, break a window, and enter, where they found him, in almost the same position, same area that Tommy was also discovered. Tommy did not have an autopsy. The Medical Examiner deduced, after having seen all the medication, that Tommy died of a heart attack. Reggie had an autopsy.The official cause of death has not been determined, but it is leaning toward heart attack, due to all the medication. Again, I was the designated key keeper. And, again, I plan for Reggie's Memorial, after I help pack up his things. His close friends aren't painfully grieving Reggie's passing. Spiritually poetic, almost like a married couple when one goes, it's not uncommon that the other shortly dies, simply of a broken heart, for Tommy was found on September 13th, and Reggie was found on January 13th, exactly 4 months to the day. Love to you always, Lloyd and Barbara, [?]
        A list of contents is included on the label of the tape.
        Tommy Hollis "A Memorial Celebration" (1 hr 37 mins)
        Roc's Film Compilation (20 mins)
        Christmas 1986
        "Africanus Instructus: Black Max" (5 mins)
        Tribute to Lyn Rustin - 2001-03-19 (last footage of Tommy singing)
        One of Tommy's voiceover gigs - 2002-01-20 ([2] mins)
      - "George White Scandals 1989", undated; JWJMSS176_0094; 1; 00:05:03 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301356)
      - "The Third Praemium Imperiale", 1995; JWJMSS176_0095; 1; 00:25:13 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301364)
      - "Seven Devils National Playwright's Conference", undated; JWJMSS176_0096; 1; 00:04:51 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301372)
      - "Lawrence Olivier #I 000-585 / 585-1003 #2/ 1003-1685 "King Lear", undated; JWJMSS176_0097; 1; 05:45:29 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301380)
      - "National Visionary Leadership Project/Highlights of 2003 Summit & Awards Gala", JWJMSS176_0098; 1; 00:19:18 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301398)
      - "National Visionary Leadership Project/NVLP Promotional Tape", undated; JWJMSS176_0099; 1; 00:04:11 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301406)
      - "TCG: Preserving the Legacy: The First Forty Years", 2001; JWJMSS176_0100; 1; 01:39:47 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301414)
      - "Soviet Ambassador Dobrynin all ONU 1984 Satellite Feed", JWJMSS176_0101; 1; U-matic S; This does not contain content on the Soviet ambassador. This tape includes a spot titled "Invisible Man". The 30-second spot, dated 1985-08-14, is an American Savings Bank commercial. This tape has not been digitized. (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301422)
      - "Shaka-Zulu miniseries, 1-3, each segment 2 hours", undated; JWJMSS176_0102; 1; 04:53:55 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301430)
      - "Shaka-Zulu miniseries, 4-5, each segment 2 hours", undated; JWJMSS176_0103; 1; 03:47:32 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301448)
      - "Wilson Tape #1, duplicate", undated; JWJ MSS 176_0104; 1; 02:02:16 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301455)
      - "Wilson Tape #2, duplicate", undated; JWJ MSS 176_0105; 1; 01:47:29 (Box 153, Item barcode 39002102301463)
      - Eugene O'Neill: A Documentary Film, part 1, 2001; JWJMSS176_0109; 1; 01:01:14; There is a timecode that runs on the bottom of the video through the entire tape. The end of Part 1 is at 00:59:30, then repeats the last minute of Part 1 at 00:59:44. (Box 153, Item barcode 39002093672799)
      - Eugene O'Neill: A Documentary Film, part 2, 2001; JWJMSS176_0110; 1; 00:55:30; There's a timecode that runs through the bottom of the entire video. (Box 153, Item barcode 39002093672807)
      - Eugene O'Neill: A Documentary Film, interviews from, 2001; JWJMSS176_0111; 1; 00:26:34; The audio has a "sync buzz" through the entire video. This tape may be a duplicate. (Box 153, Item barcode 39002093672815)
  - Sound Recordings
    All sound recordings are cassette and 1/4" reel to reel tape formats.
    - Productions
      - " Antique Bearers ", 1978; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180395)
      - " An Attempt at Flying ", undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180403)
      - " Christopher Columbus, Madonna and Jesus #3 Christ last speech #1", 1998
        - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180437)
        - Storm - Country, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180445)
        - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180452)
      - " Cobb ", 1990
        - Music Sources, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180411)
          Contents include: National Anthem, Concert Arts, Eastman Winds and The National Game
        - Music, March 15; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180429)
      - Fences
        - "Showtapes 1 & 2 duplicate", undated; 1 (Box 161, Folder 1802, Item barcode 39002137180262)
        - Intermission Demo, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180460)
        - Preshow Demo, 1985 April 28; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180478)
        - "Old Dog Blue", Yale Repertory Theatre, 1985 April 4; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180486)
        - Preshow Music; Intermission Music, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180494)
        - Songs, Soul Stirrers; Sam Cooke / Fences, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180502)
          Contents are listed below.
          Tammy
          Almost in Your Arms
          I Thank God
          Desire Me
          My Foolish Heart
          The Lonesome Road
          Canadian Sunset
          Oh! Look at Me Now
          Jesus Gave Me Water
          Out on a Hill
          Sinner run to Jesus
          Faith and Grace
          Pilgrim of Sorrow
          In a Few More Days
          Touch the Hem of his Garment
          Feel Like My Time Ain't Long
          The Lord is My Shepard
        - Music, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180510)
        - Cue W (dog), undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180528)
        - Environments Rep VI, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180536)
          Contents include Friday evening, Saturday morning and Saturday afternoon
        - Environment, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180544)
      - " Hedda Gabler ", 1981-1982
        - Music, Grieg played by Rubinstein; Ballade op. 24, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180569)
        - Hedda Gabler, undated; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180577)
          A list of contents is included.
          Opening
          Act I, Sc. 1-2
          Intermission (whole piece)
          Act II, Sc. 1-2 (2 choices)
          Tinkering
          Dance Music (2 choices)
          End
      - " Joe Turner's Come and Gone ", 1988 March 27; 1 (Box 162, Item barcode 39002137180551)
        A list of music from The Barrymore Theater
        The Story of Joe Turner
        How Happy I Am
        I Heard the Angels Singing
        Wonder Where My Old Mother Is
        Soon My Work Will All Be Done
        I Belong to the Band
        If I Had My Way
        How Long Has It Been
        Standing at the Crossroads
        Keep Your Lamps Trimmed and Burning
        Joe Turner's Come and Gone Opening
      - " Joe Turner's Come and Gone ", circa 1985
        - Research, Tape A, 1986 February 24; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180601)
          A list of contents is below. Included: Robert Johnson, Curtis Jones, Peter Chatman and Tony Hollins
          Crossroads Blues
          Terraplane Blues
          Come On in My Kitchen
          Walking Blues
          Last Fair Deal Gone Down
          32-20 Blues
          Kind Hearted Woman Blues
          If I Had Possession Over Judgement Day
          Preaching Blues
          When You Got a Good Friend
          Rambling on My Mind
          Rambling on My Mind [2]
          Stones in My Passway
          Traveling Riverside Blues
          Milkcow's Calf Blues
          Me and the Devil Blues
          Hellbound on My Trail
          Blues and Troubles
          Miss Ora Lee Blues
          Crawlin King Snake
          Little Son Joe Just Had to Holler
        - Research, Tape B, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180585)
          A list of contents is included from miscellaneous folk songs and lullabies to Reverand Pearly Brown.
          How Long Has It Been Since You Been Home
          Pure Religion
          Help Me to Understand
          Keep Your Lamp Trimmed and Burnin
          Mama Don't Tear My Clothes
          Kansas City Blues
          Salty Dog Blues
          Momma's Gonna Buy Him a Little Lap Dog
          Soon as My Back's Turned
          She Done Got Ugly
          Now Your Man Done Gone
        - D. Andrews versions; "Czar", 1986 March; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180593)
        - Preshow; Soundcues, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180619)
        - Joe Turner / Ethel Waters, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180627)
          Joe Turner
          Rural South (1934)
          Did You See My Brown (2)
          Pulling the Skiff
          Uncle Rabbit
          Sea Lion Woman
          Ring Bell
          Shortening Bread
          I Hear the Angels Sing
          Sampson and Delilah
          Wonder Where My Old Mother
          I'll Be So Glad When Payday Come
      - " A Lion and the Jewel ", 1977; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180635)
      - " Ma Rainey's Black Bottom ", circa 1985
        A note is included with these audiocassettes. It reads: Dear Lloyd, Here it is! Please let me know if anything bothers you. I will do my best to make connections. I am very proud of the work (it's been hard and long but well worth it). If there is anyone you wish to credit also let me know. It's been a real pleasure working with you. I'm sure this album will be wonderful for both of us. All My Best, Mike [Berniker]
        - "Prove It On Me"; "Ma Rainey's Black Bottom"; "MRBB - Levee's (piano), undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180643)
        - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom, sides A and B, 1985 February 26; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180650)
        - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom, sides C and D, 1985 February 26; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180668)
        - Theresa Merritt sings Ma Rainey, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180676)
          Hear Me Talkin to You
          Daddy Goodbye
          Trust No Man
          Leaving This Morning
          Wringin and Twistin Blues
          See See Rider
        - Ma Rainey, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180692)
          Entire "Ma Rainey" album. Contents listed below.
          August's Suggestions
          Hear Me Talking to You
          Daddy Goodbye Blues
          Sweet Rough Man
        - National Public Radio "Ma Rainey", August Wilson, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180700)
        - Theresa Merritt sings Ma Rainey's BB - Songs, Tape 2, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180718)
        - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom, sides A and B, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180684)
        - Ma Rainey's Black Bottom, sides C and D, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180726)
        - "Ma Rainey"; Bessie Smith #1, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180734)
          A list of contents is included with this audiocassette.
          Traveling Blues
          Jailhouse Blues
          St. Louis Gal
          Sam Jones Blues
          Graveyard Dream Blues
          Cemetery Blues
          Far Away Blues
          I'm Going Back to My Used to Be
          Wasted Life Blues
          Dirty No-Gooder's Blues
          Blue Spirit Blues
          Worn Out Papa Blues
          You Don't Understand
          Don't Cry Baby
          Keep It to Yourself
      - " Major Barbara ", 1983
        - Sample tape, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180742)
          Immenso Grübilo Wedding March
          Men and Mountains
          Fanfare "Stadt Wier"
          March for Military Band
          March in E Flat
        - Salvation Army, Sample Tape 2, undated; 1 (Box 163, Item barcode 39002137180759)
          Contents include: "West Ham March", sample of concertina playing "Onward Christian Soldiers", in- and -out-of-tune versions of "Onward Christian Soldiers"
      - " Major Barbara ", 1983
        - Sample Tape 3; military music, possibilities for set change into armory / Salvation Army, undated; 1 (Box 164, Item barcode 39002137180767)
          A list of contents is included. In addition, the first three takes of "Onward Christian Soldiers" recorded the bank simultaneously on a 2nd track. A note explains: "it allows versatility on when the band comes in at scene changes". The next six takes of "Onward Christian Soldiers" do not have a band recorded underneath.
          "Men and Mountains"
          "Fanfare 'Stadt Wien'"
          "March for Military Band" No. 1 in F
          "March in E Flat"
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 1
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 11
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 12
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 2
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 6
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 9
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 13
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 14
          "Onward Christian Soldiers", final take
          Band playing "Onward Christian Soldiers", in tune
          Band playing "Onward Christian Soldiers", out of tune
          Band playing "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 12
          Band playing "Onward Christian Soldiers", take 11
          Possible set change, concertina
          "West Ham March", take 1
          "West Ham March", final take